# **Wanghley Soares Martins**

## Data Scientist | fullstack developer | Junior researcher

Brasília, DF, Brazil | +55 (61) 98512 7961 | wanghleys@gmail.com

# □ wanghley.github.io/ □ linkedin.com/in/wanghley/



### Summary

Wanghley is currently a student at the Federal Institute of Brasília and a junior researcher at the National Council for Scientific and Technological Development (CNPq).

He has experience in the field of Computer Science, with an emphasis on Web Development, Programming and Electronics, acting mainly on the following themes: mobile programming, desktop programming, fullstack programming, artificial intelligence, data science, image processing and transmission, education and data visualization.

## **Experiências**

Mentor

Apr 2020 - nowadays

Mais Startup

Research and innovation mentor in the pure and applied mathematics area of the + Science research incentive program

CTO Oct 2019 – Jan 2020

ScoutNet

Technology leader and risk manager at startup ScoutNet

associated sept 2019 - nowadays

Nexa Distrito Federal

NEXADF apprentice associate, fostering entrepreneurship and youth protasgonism

Junior Researcher aug 2019 - nowadays National Council for Scientific and Technological Development

Researcher in computer science in Data Visualization Strategy for Individualized Medicine

Junior Researcher

jan 2019 - dez 2019

Instituto Federal de Brasília

Computer science researcher in the research project Monitoring biomedical signs of Parkinson's disease

Volunteer Researcher

oct 2018 - nowadays

Instituto Federal do Paraná

Volunteer researcher in the area of transmission and digital image processing in the research project called Avatar

#### **Skills**

Problem solving

C++

Strategy

Team work

Research

Mobile

JavaScript

agile development

Data visualization

Communication

leadership

Python

lava

#### **Education**

Computer technician integrated to high school

jan 2018 - nowadays

Instituto Federal de Brasília - Campus Brasília

Student of technical course in computer science integrated with high school

## Additional training

Introduction to Calculus Sydney University	- may 2020
Computer Vision Basics University at Buffalo	- apr 2020
Creative problem solving University of Minnesota	- apr 2020
Data visualization with Python IBM	- jan. 2020
Bioinformatics for the discovery of new viruses FIOCRUZ	- oct 2019
Visualization of Protein Structures FIOCRUZ	- oct 2019